indesignskills.com 2018-12-24

# Privacy Policy | InDesign Skills

Hi, we’re InDesignSkills and welcome to our privacy policy. This policy sets out how we handle personal information.

#### ADVERTISERS

Third-party advertisers featured on InDesignSkills may collect tracking information in a different manner than is set out in this Privacy Policy. The only information that they will be able to track is basic Website usage information; e-mail addresses are not passed on to advertisers for any reason even if they are provided to InDesignSkills voluntarily.

#### COOKIES

We use cookies to store visitor preferences, record user-specific information on what pages users access or visit, customize Website content based on visitor browser type or other information that the visitor sends.

#### USE OF INFORMATION PROVIDED BY USER

When you sign up for our newsletter, we will send you our monthly newsletter as well as the occasional sponsored newsletter and invitations to try new products. Your email address and any personal information is not shared with any of our sponsors. You will have the option to opt-out of the newsletter via a link, which appears in each newsletter. Your personal information is not used by subsidiary organizations or businesses related to InDesignSkills, unless clearly disclosed for specific situations.

#### YOUR CONSENT

When signing up for our newsletter, or when downloading some of the free resources available through our website, you will be required to give your consent to be subscribed to our newsletter via either email confirmation or an opt-in checkbox. An unsubscribe link is included at the bottom of each newsletter. When submitting your email address, your IP address is saved as a form of proof of content to subscribe to our newsletter. By using our Web site you consent to our collection and use of your personal information as described in this Privacy Policy. If we change our privacy policies and procedures, we will post those changes on our Web site to keep you aware of what information we collect, how we use it and under what circumstances we may disclose it.

#### INFORMATION OWNERSHIP

All e-mails or other forms of communication received by InDesignSkills are the property of InDesignSkills and may be used for editorial or technical improvements to the Website at our discretion without any form of compensation being owed to the sender of said communications.

#### INFORMATION SECURITY

Our service providers have appropriate security measures in place to protect against the loss, misuse or alteration of information that we have collected from you at our Website. Information provided by Website visitors is held in confidence and used for editorial and technical improvements to the Website.

#### AFFILIATE PROGRAMS, SPONSORED POSTS, ETC

From time to time we may choose to use affiliate links and/or sponsored posts as an effort to generate extra income to our website. The appearance of such links or sponsored content in this blog is determined by its informational or inspirational value and not by its commercial value to us. We will only promote products and services that we like and feel are beneficial to our audience.

#### THIRD PARTY ADVERTISING

We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads and collect information when users visit our site. These companies may use information (not including your name, address, email address or telephone number) about your visits to this and other websites in order to provide advertisements on our site, other websites and other forms of media about goods and services of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, check out <http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp>

#### RETENTION AND SECURITY

Your Personal Information may be stored and processed in any country where we have facilities or in which we engage third party service providers. By using the Website, you consent to the transfer of information to countries outside your country of residence, which may have different data protection rules than in your country. Such information will be subject to the laws of the country in which it is held, and may be subject to disclosure to the governments, courts or law enforcement or regulatory agencies of such other country, pursuant to the laws of such country.

We will maintain your Personal Information for as long as a business need exists, or as required by applicable laws, regulations, or government orders.

#### RIGHTS

On written request and subject to proof of identity, you may access the Personal Information that we hold, and ask that any necessary corrections be made, where applicable, as authorized or required by law. However, to make sure that the Personal Information we maintain about you is accurate and up to date, please inform us immediately of any change in your Personal Information.

#### CHANGES TO THIS POLICY

Changes to our privacy policy in the future will be posted on this page.

If you have any questions about our privacy policy you can contact us at the follow email address: info@indesignskills.com.

This is version 2 of our privacy policy – last revised 23 May 2018.

(The previous version of this policy is available [here](http://www.indesignskills.com/privacy-v1/).)
